pncbank.com 2007-06-19

# Privacy Policy

_PNC will post online any changes to the Website Customer Information Privacy Policy and the Consumer Information Privacy Principles on or before the effective date of such changes. You will be able to determine the date of the last change by noting the effective date of the policies._

Website Customer Information Privacy Policy

We respect the privacy of our customers and are committed to protecting their information on our Web sites with the same care we utilize for all PNC transactions.

PNC does not automatically collect personal information from visitors to its Web sites. PNC does use tools, such as cookies or click stream auditing, for our own internal uses, such as recommending products and services and gathering Web analytics. Cookies are small pieces of information that a Web site stores on a visitor's Web browser to remind the site about the visitor the next time they visit the site. PNC does not store confidential or sensitive information in cookies. PNC uses cookies to enhance our customers' online banking session by making navigation easier and providing important security features. For certain applications, such as Online Banking, cookies are a requirement because they help protect the privacy of a customer's transactions by, for example, automatically terminating the online session if the customer forgets to log out.

Cookies cannot be used to capture your e-mail address, obtain data from your hard drive or gain confidential or sensitive information about you. Additionally, cookies cannot be read by a Web site other than the one that set the cookie. Some Web sites, however, use cookies to obtain information from your browser. You can set your browser to notify you before accepting a cookie, so that you can control whether you accept or reject a cookie. Please click on Controlling Cookies for more information. 

Click stream auditing includes information such as a web surfer's IP address, web pages which have been viewed or acted upon by a web surfer, date and time, domain type, and when a web surfer has responded to an advertisement. We may occasionally combine this information with individual information on an aggregate level to determine the effectiveness of our advertising.

This version of the Website Customer Information Privacy Policy is effective 04/01/07.

_THE PNC FINANCIAL SERVICES GROUP, INC. CONSUMER INFORMATION PRIVACY PRINCIPLES_

Introduction  
The PNC Financial Services Group, Inc. ("PNC") family of companies is committed to treating and using personal financial information about you responsibly. These Privacy Principles explain what personal information we collect, why we collect it, how we protect personal information, and how and why in certain cases we may share such information among PNC companies or with select other parties. We also tell you how to exercise your personal information sharing choices. If you have already notified us of your Information Sharing Choices, you do not need to notify us again. These principles are effective 04/01/07 and may be amended from time to time.

Our Consumer Information Privacy Principles apply to personal information collected or used when PNC companies offer financial services to you for personal, family or household purposes. The services may include deposit, lending, investment advisory, brokerage and insurance services. This disclosure is made on behalf of the following PNC companies: PNC Bank, National Association; PNC Bank, Delaware; J.J.B. Hilliard, W.L. Lyons, Inc.; PNC Investments LLC; PNC Capital Markets LLC; PNC Insurance Services, LLC; PNC Equipment Finance LLC; Harris Williams LLC and PNC Merchant Services Company. 

We Collect Information As Needed to Identify You and Serve You as a Customer  
We collect information from and about you in order to identify you as our customer, establish and manage customer accounts, complete customer transactions, understand customer needs through market research, market products and services we believe meet customer needs, and comply with legal and regulatory requirements.

_Examples of the types of information we collect are:_

Information we receive from you, such as: 

Contact Information (such as name, address, and telephone number). We use contact information, for example, to identify you, send you information about our products and services, and call or write you about your accounts.

Identification Information (such as a social security number). We may need your social security number, for example, to obtain a credit report when you apply for credit with us, report interest earnings or mortgage interest payments to the IRS, or comply with other legal requirements.

Financial Profile Information (such as income, assets, liabilities). We use this information, for example, to process applications and make appropriate product and service recommendations to help you get the most from your relationship with PNC.

Information about your transactions and experiences with PNC companies. This information, such as your account balances, payment or overdraft history, parties to transactions and account usage, permits us, for example, to process your requests quickly, recommend appropriate products, and price products and services competitively on the basis of your entire relationship with us.

Information about your transactions with other companies. We may use this information, for example, when you apply for credit or to verify information you have provided to us.

Information about you from consumer reporting agencies  (such as your credit history and credit worthiness). We use this information when, for example, we process applications, monitor and collect existing accounts, make "pre-approved" offers and as otherwise permitted by law.

Information from market research companies (such as purchasing patterns). We use market research information, for example, to develop products we believe our customers will find most useful.

Policies and Procedures   
PNC companies use advanced technology and information management techniques to implement security, audit and control programs designed to protect the confidentiality and security of the information we collect. PNC limits employee access to customer information to those employees we believe have a legitimate business need for the information. We have adopted policies, procedures, employee orientation, training and education programs, and communication programs designed for the protection of customer information. It is the responsibility of each PNC company employee to comply with our Consumer Information Privacy Principles.

We May Share Information Within the PNC Family of Companies To Improve Our Services to You  
PNC offers financial services to consumers through its family of affiliated companies that provide, for example, deposit, lending, investment advisory, brokerage, insurance, trust, and related products. 

By sharing information about you and your accounts, we are able to offer you the convenience of round-the clock customer service, combined statements, simple application procedures for a variety of financial services, and special discounts or other benefits.

Within the family of PNC companies, we share:

  * Financial profile information, for example, income, assets and liabilities, that you provide to us on credit applications or elsewhere;
  * Information that we receive from third parties not affiliated with us, such as consumer reporting agencies and market research companies.

You may request that we do not share these two types of information among ourselves except where one PNC company performs services for another. Please see "It's Your Choice" to find out how to make this request.1

_1 _Vermont residents only_ : PNC will not share financial profile or credit report information among the PNC family of companies without your consent._

We also share within the PNC family of companies contact and identification information, for example, name, address, telephone and social security numbers, that you provide to us. We also share information about your transactions with us, for example, account balances, payment or overdraft history, parties to transactions, and account usage. We will do so even if you request that we not share other types of information.

We May Share Information Outside the PNC Family of Companies in Certain Cases  
It is our policy not to sell, rent or otherwise provide customer information to outside companies so they can market their non-financial products or services. From time to time, we may offer our customers the opportunity to purchase non-financial products and services offered by outside third parties, but we will not disclose customer information to these third parties unless our customers authorize us to do so.

The sections below describe the types of companies and third parties with whom, and the situations when, we may share customer information outside the PNC family of companies.

Service Providers and Suppliers  
From time to time, PNC companies may use outside companies or suppliers to perform services for PNC, such as printing checks for our customers, preparing and mailing customer account statements, appraising property offered as collateral, verifying property ownership, processing customer transactions and assisting us in providing account benefit programs.

We may also use outside companies to perform market research and analysis for us by contacting our customers, as well as non-customers, to ask their opinions about our current or proposed products and services. Generally, we provide market researchers only with customer contact information, such as name, address, and telephone number. Occasionally, we provide them with customer account information, such as type of account, balance, and whether a customer banks at a branch, at an ATM, or online.

Sometimes we use outside companies to assist us in marketing our own PNC products and services or products and services, such as mortgages and insurance, that we offer jointly with other financial institutions. Generally, we provide our marketing service providers only with customer contact information, such as name, address and telephone number.

Before we disclose customer information to any of our service providers or suppliers, we require them to agree to keep our customer information confidential and secure and to use it only as authorized by us.

We May Share Limited Information With Select Financial Institutions for Marketing Purposes  
In order to offer our customers certain financial products, such as mortgages or insurance, we may enter into joint marketing agreements with select financial institutions outside the family of PNC companies that specialize in providing these products.

Generally, we provide these financial institutions only with customer contact information, such as name, address, and telephone number. When we offer certain insurance products, such as credit insurance, we may provide account information, such as the amount of the loan or mortgage, maturity date, and monthly payment amount. We do not give these financial institutions customer account numbers as part of a joint marketing agreement or program.2

We select financial institutions we work with under joint marketing agreements very carefully and require them to agree to keep our customer information confidential and use it only as authorized by us.

You may request that we do not share your information with other financial institutions for joint marketing purposes. Please see "It's Your Choice" to find out how to make this request.

_2 _Vermont Residents only_ : PNC will share only contact information with financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements._

Other Circumstances  
We may share customer information with unaffiliated third parties when our customers request or give us permission to do so or when we are permitted or required to do so by law.

Some examples are: 

  * When we complete your transactions, such as paying your checks, following your online payment directions, purchasing securities for your account, or processing insurance applications;
  * When we respond to your service requests;
  * When we share information with consumer reporting agencies;
  * When we verify account status for merchants you want to pay by check;
  * When we offer account benefits, such as credit card and other reward programs;
  * When we transfer information in connection with a proposed or actual sale of accounts, or a proposed or actual sale of all or part of a business unit;
  * When we suspect fraud or for risk management purposes;
  * When we are required by a federal, state, or local law or regulation to do so;
  * When we receive a subpoena or are ordered by a court to do so.

Former Customers  
We do not disclose information about former customers to outside companies except as may be permitted or required by law.  Examples of when we may share information about former customers are listed above.

State Privacy Laws  
We will also comply with state privacy laws to the extent they apply.

Online Information Policies  
We respect the privacy of our customers and are committed to protecting their information on our websites with the same care we utilize for all PNC company transactions. To view our current online privacy notice, visit us at www.pnc.com.

It's Your Choice

Option 1 - Limit Sharing Information Within PNC Family  
Request this Information Sharing option if you do not want us to share among our family of PNC companies financial profile information, for example, income, assets and liabilities, contained in applications and financial statements, or information we receive from third parties that are not affiliated with us, such as consumer reporting agencies and market research companies.

We will continue to share among our family of PNC companies: (i) contact information, for example, name, address, telephone number; (ii) identification information, for example, social security number; and (iii) information that relates to our experiences or transactions with you or your accounts, for example, account balances, payment history, parties to transactions and account usage.

Option 2 - Limit Sharing Information With Other Financial Institutions for Marketing Purposes  
Request this Information Sharing option if you do not want us to share any information with other financial institutions for the purpose of joint marketing of their financial services.

To exercise your choice of Information Sharing options: 

  * Write to us at: PNC Information Sharing Options, PO Box 96066, Pittsburgh, PA 15226, or
  * Call us any time at 1-800-762-2118, or
  * Stop by any PNC office.

When writing, please indicate which Information Sharing option or options you are requesting and include your name, address and phone number. Providing an account number or social security number would be helpful but is optional. 

PNC will process your request as soon as possible. However, you may receive communications for a short time based on information we shared prior to processing your request. 

If you have joint accounts, we will treat a request by one party to the account as applying to both parties to the account. The information sharing restriction request(s) will apply to accounts that each joint account holder has in his or her own name and any accounts the joint account holders have with each other.
